A couple weeks ago, I
interviewed a billionaire in Beverly Hills.
Excuse me, sir.
Question for you.
How old were you when you became a millionaire?
You have to ask a millionaire.
What do you mean?
I'm a billionaire.
You're a billionaire?
Yeah.
How old were you when you became a billionaire?
Oh, in my 50s.
In your 50s?
Yeah.
And what line of business were you in?
The hospitality business.
What were you doing in hospitality?
I owned hotels.
Yeah, all over the world, 35 countries.
So you're a business owner.
I was, I was.
Hilton owns my company today.
Hilton bought your company?
Hilton bought my company.
Wow.
Eventually, yeah.
I actually created a company that was
worth $2.2 billion, $3.3 billion equity value.
Actually?
Actually, enterprise value, yeah.
Wow.
That video got over 100 million views across social media.
And like he said, he became a billionaire by
selling his company to Hilton for several billion dollars.
So I just flew out here to Beverly Hills to come
meet up with and interview the legend once again at his house.
That's Steven Klubeck.
And I flew out here to get the secrets from
him on how somebody can become a billionaire in today's world
and become successful.
Just like him.
So let's waste no more time.
Let's go meet up with Steven and
go see what he has to say.
Come on.
All right, you guys.
So we just got to Steven's
house out here in Beverly Hills.
We're going to go link up with him and go get not
a million, but a billion dollars worth of game from you guys,
from an absolute legend out here in Beverly Hills.
Come on, you guys.
What's up, guys?
What's going on, man?
How you doing?
Yeah, we're doing a video with Steven.
Yeah.
You guys have your...
IDs?
Yeah.
IDs, please.
Yeah, I got you.
Are you from...
There they are.
Wow.
How you doing?
It's great to see you.
The star of stars.
Great to see you.
What's going on?
You know, the last time I saw
you, we did over 100 million views online.
You're a rock star.
I appreciate it.
What you have going and what you're
creating for young entrepreneurs is so special.
I'm telling you, I've never seen anything like it.
You've got magic and everyone should pay attention.
Like I said, our last
video did over 100 million views.
I can't believe we did over 100 million views.
And you know what?
It's all real.
You are 100%.
Unscripted and real.
If anyone says anything else, they don't understand.
It's no different when I did an undercover boss.
Everyone's like, that's fake.
No, that's real.
That is totally unscripted.
And that's the way the world should be.
The people saw you started negative
$20 million in the hospitality business.
Yeah.
Flipped it around.
Sold a company for how much to Hilton?
$3.3 billion equity value.
EV, yeah.
It was a great role.
We fixed the most broken of companies.
So for the people that don't know, after exiting
your company, having a ton of success in the
business world, what are you doing right now?
You know, the most unthinkable.
My whole career has been unthinkable.
I never dreamt of the things that I've done.
I never thought that I would help create
the brand of the United States of America, Brand
USA, to enhance tourism and travel
after the lost decade of travel.
So you ran tourism for all the United States?
Helped create Brand USA.
I was in charge of tourism for the United States.
I reported to the Oval Office.
And I kind of ruffled some feathers.
But when I got done, the
return on investment was so outsized.
The president of the United States was blown away.
Because I made everyone look good.
No trophies for me.
No hair gel.
No red.
No red carpet.
I just roll up my
sleeves and get the work done.
And I want everyone to become rock stars.
So no pride of authorship.
I want everyone to do well
and aspire to do great things.
I thought I was going to be a surgeon.
Didn't end up doing that.
Didn't want to go to school for another 16 years.
Ended up going into real
estate shopping centers, then hotels.
Done a lot of politics and
policy along the way as an activist.
Helping out.
Always helping.
Rolling up my sleeves.
Bus point or boardroom.
I think I told you that.
And I just love serving.
So it's so funny.
When I did Undercover Boss, I never really understood.
I really.
I thought they were going to hurt me.
They weren't going to hurt my brand.
But it helped my brand.
Because it made me a better leader.
Because I listened to my team.
I listened to my customers.
And it's not what I think or you think.
It's what the customer thinks.
So I am now more ingrained in politics and policy.
And I'm running for governor of California.
I never thought I'd be doing that.
It wasn't on my bucket list.
Now I came out from Austin.
Back out here to Beverly Hills for part two.
And I want this to be a master class.
For all the aspiring
young entrepreneurs, professionals out there.
On how you built your success.
We're going to make that happen.
I'm happy to talk to you about it.
Absolutely.
Let's get into some questions then.
Good.
Let's do it.
You want to go sit in the other room?
We'll chat about it.
Let's do it.
All right.
Good.
The first hotel that you had built was in 1990.
It was the Twin Towers in Las Vegas.
Or what was it?
Polo Towers.
The Polo Towers.
Were there some challenges back then during
the 90s that you had to deal with?
I'd never built a hotel.
I built shopping centers.
And I built one shopping center,
fortunately, that had every problem imaginable.
My contractors went broke.
I paid for lumber.
I paid for twice.
I didn't understand lien releases.
All my tenants went broke.
The economy was falling apart.
And I had to build this thing myself.
And then I found out I had to
build a retaining wall, which is wickedly expensive.
That was not on the plans.
So I had to build this thing myself.
I had to learn how to
really build, read plans, and build.
And I'm like, okay, I'm
going to blow my brains out.
And I weathered through it.
I ended up losing the shopping center.
I didn't go broke.
But I lost it.
Because everyone lost everything at that time.
But I survived.
But I was able to design and build a hotel.
And I did it.
And I was 29 years old.
And I was able to build a hotel.
And I did it.
And Poe Towers was the largest hotel timeshare
complex ever built at one time in the world.
And we did it in Las Vegas.
And I did it with my father.
Because I worked for my father at that time.
It was on time, on budget.
And we got it done.
And it was just a wild success.
But it was very, very difficult.
Nobody had ever done that.
So talk to me about when
you're starting out, 29 years old.
You have no idea at that
time how to actually build a hotel.
What are some of those relationships that you went to
go establish to be able to make all that happen?
I always kept things fresh.
I always listened to my
customer to see what they wanted.
Because I used the term polo.
Polo is kind of a fancy game.
But my customer was a big market.
So I didn't want to make
the project uncomfortable for the customer.
So it's not that staid old English look.
It's very modern.
And of course, funny, Ralph Lauren sued me.
Because we used the name Polo Towers.
I fought Ralph Lauren.
Because I had marked Polo
Towers for hotel, timeshare, and casino.
They never did.
We ended up spending some serious dough.
And I ended up getting
that brand name against Ralph Lauren.
You want to talk about brass balls.
But look.
I'm big on trademarks.
I'm big on domains.
Big on brand.
So you just keep your
head down and fight the fight.
You guys, Steven has been going crazy so far.
And I'm about to get right back to the interview.
But before we do that, I want to tell you the number
one thing that I've learned from spending time with billionaires like Steven.
See, I've interviewed over 15 billionaires in the
last three years and over a thousand multi-millionaires.
And you want to know the number one secret, the number
one shortcut to success and how they became millionaires or billionaires?
It was mentorship.
It's finding the people that you want to be.
Exactly like and learning everything that you can from them.
The only way to go from point A to point
B in life and business and anything is getting mentors.
A lot of you guys reach out and ask me.
Hey, how do I get mentors?
How do you, meaning myself, connect with the millionaires
and the billionaires that I interview every single week?
And for that reason, since that's the number one thing that you guys ask me, I'm going to give you right
now the ability to come get mentored every single week from the billionaires and the billionaires that I interview on this channel.
Guys, I built one of
the largest communities for business owners.
In the entire world called the school of mentors.
And like I said, guys, every single week, I bring in a multi-millionaire or billionaire
entrepreneur that built or sold a company for eight figures, nine figures or a billion dollars.
Just like Steven.
In fact, Steven literally mentored my community a couple months ago where all the members got to
get on a two hour long zoom call with him and ask them specific questions about their business.
He taught our community how to get access to money
and capital to be able to buy assets like real estate.
Even if you have no money to your name.
He taught our community.
How to start growing eventually sell their business just like he did for
over three billion dollars to one of the biggest companies in the entire world.
So if you guys want to come get mentored every week
from the most successful business owners in the entire world for free.
All you have to do is go down
to the link in the description of this video.
There's one of my private entrepreneur community.
The school of mentors.
I can't wait to see on the inside.
That being said, let's get back to the interview.
Come on.
All right.
So we're at our next location.
You got a beautiful office here.
But one of the first things that stood out to me
when I came in and you know greeted you was this.
Tell me about this right here.
Iron Man.
So I've got two nicknames Iron Man and Wolverine.
I cut the nickname Iron Man because unfortunately I was walking in a crosswalk
going to dinner and I was hit by a car at 40 miles per hour.
I looked out the corner of my eye.
I saw it coming.
I jumped and hit the hood with full-on faceplant dented the living crap out of that car flipped like a stuntman, which I have no idea how I did
it and landed like this on my feet and forearms and the people at the Starbucks were going like is he dead and I'm on the ground like this.
I'm like I'm good as I'm
gushing blood out of my face.
I got a free ride to the hospital got 40 stitches in my face and I got the nickname Iron Man and the reason
I got Wolverine because I heal quick and it played my head over and over because this stuff does not get out of your head.
But gives you a new lease on life transformation again.
This is a saying I have and
I told you this before stay present.
This is really important in life.
They say that those who are living in the past are depressed those living in the future are anxious,
but the ones who are present are the ones who are, you know, calm and at peace with himself.
How important has that been?
For you getting to the point where I can stay present has been another leap in my growth and my journey and it's not easy to get to
it's not you know, we all have journeys and you got to step in some potholes and you got to get beaten up a little bit getting beaten up.
You got to understand is good because it's growth but getting to a
point where you can stay present focusing on the person you're with listening.
That's when opportunity presents itself.
I since we're in the
presence of Iron Man right here.
I wanted to ask you I interviewed a really successful internet marketer one
time and he said you want to know who has the best personal brands.
It's actually superheroes.
It's people that fundamentally stand for and against something
and for the people that are watching right now.
They may not know but you
invented with the government brand USA.
You're all about branding talked to me about what it takes to build a brand that
has longevity in his and is in the game for years integrity discipline and using your experience.
It takes decades and decades to build a brand.
It takes minutes to kill a brand.
It's all about integrity.
If you lie to me you
bust my trust don't bust my trust.
You're done.
It is the most important concept in my ethos.
If I find somebody that is not a person of
integrity, but did to me they lie to me you done.
I'm always honest.
I'm not perfect.
None of us are perfect.
We all make mistakes.
We grow we pivot we get better.
No one gets to a hundred
percent, but our brand is sacrosanct.
We don't tarnish the brand.
Okay, never ever ever tarnish the brand and if someone around
you hurt your brand, they don't respect you respect is very important.
Remember I talked to you respect.
We all have a responsibility to one
another and we got to show results.
It all goes to brand.
Who are you as a brand?
Who do you want to become?
You create your own brand your choices.
You want to be a leader or do
you want to be a part of the ensemble?
Who are you?
I'm a leader.
I make tough decisions.
I'm not here to please everyone.
But if I please the super majority and give my customers
a little more than they bargained for I've done the job.
What was one of the toughest decisions that you had to make if somebody lied to a customer you have to
be able to hold the line in your brand and I had to fire my number one salesperson in the world.
My number one salesperson in the world.
Because they created a cancer.
Within the organization and everyone says don't know you can't fire that
person don't remove that person when I remove that person from the organization.
We grew by 20% tough decision.
Everyone said don't do it.
I did it.
That's what leaders do and you
need brass balls to do that.
You got brass balls.
I do good.
I've got them.
You want to see him?
I guess I have to I'm going to
show you there right there on my desk.
I got to see you.
Okay, I'm going to show you.
So this is a gift.
I got Steven.
I know you don't need another.
Set but I thought you may show these
off as a trophy for the biggest ones ever.
I love you pops my father.
So he did actually give
me brass balls physically and spiritually.
How did you build your first hotel?
What was that process?
Like I went around to all the great hotels and I study, you
know, I spent some time you got to do diligence anything you do.
I always do my due diligence always I traveled and I wanted to see you
know, what works what didn't work and I talked to some of the great experts.
I use I studied the
likes of Four Seasons and Ritz-Carlton.
And Marriott to see the differences and there was a lane
for an entrepreneur because those companies had become corporate like entities.
They didn't have that entrepreneurial spirit where the chairman CEO founder would actually talk
to the guest would actually create the script at the front desk wide open opportunity.
So you went afraid to
go and compete against those Giants.
I ended up competing against those Giants and the
greatest gift I got was when Marriott on Wall Street.
We would make our financial presentation.
We were unique Marriott copied.
Our deck and my CFO told me that Marriott copied our deck
and he was so upset and I'm like, what are you talking about?
This is like the greatest
trophy I can get my life.
Marriott just copied us now.
They couldn't replicate us because we were nimble.
What were you doing?
So differently from everybody else that
they were wanting to replicate you.
We were founding entrepreneurs now Marriott started way back when as a founding entrepreneur,
but it got corporate upon corporate upon corporate almost government like a rule book.
We were flexible.
We became a battleship that could move like a speedboat.
That's because the chairman CEO founder myself.
Could talk about any job in the business.
If you want to talk about technology, I hope write the code
for our back of house software tax accounting debits credits facilities management.
I can make a bed.
How involved do you think the owner should be in the different aspects of the business people talk about a lot in today's world about delegating how involved were
you in the different parts of the business as you were scaling your company from one hotel to over 435 and how many countries you said 35 countries 35 countries.
You have to love what you do.
So I would always just pop up in different departments.
And listen to what our team was
doing to make sure we were on message.
So I'd go at 50,000 feet at the
board level all the way to making a bed.
And if you want to see how our
towels were placed in our bathrooms, I did it.
I shot a video of me doing it.
So every single housekeeper was doing it exactly as I wanted it with the tag in the back
and I even under each bed had a tent card placed that said yes, we clean here too.
That's how meticulous I was
because no job in the business.
Was outside my realm of understanding and
everyone knew that I'll sweep the floor.
I'll cook you a meal.
I'll ask you what you like to eat.
I'll go cook it for you.
I will serve it to you.
I will sit at the table and listen to your story
and then I will clean the table because I'm in service.
Can I delegate sure I could delegate but I teach a
coach but they see that I can do the job too.
So it's having that experience at every level of the business, which will really
guide you to your success because everyone on the team knows we have no titles.
We're all part of the business.
We're all part of the same team
and it goes circles back to brand.
Don't mess with the brand.
Talk to me about 9-11.
You dealt with some adversity during
2001 because you're in the hotel business.
9-11 was very interesting because
during 9-11 there were no flights.
Everything was grounded.
I had no guests.
No one had any guests.
So we had to recreate how we were going to market because there were
no flights and I actually had to call my banks because I was nervous.
That till was not ringing.
It was zero cash registers
went to zero zero for everyone.
What did I do?
I called my bank every day.
To the point where they said, can you call us every three days because I wanted to let
them know what was up and I had to actually borrow some more money to get through it.
But it goes to integrity.
You tell them the good the bad the ugly and
it was ugly because we didn't know what was happening.
Very nerve-racking.
You couldn't go to anyone ask questions for advice because
it never happened before and these things happen in life.
When I told you about unintended consequences.
These are some of the unintended consequences things.
We can't even dream up.
So how are you going to pivot?
Always tell the truth because I've asked the bankers.
What are we doing different?
Is everyone talking to you?
Like we're talking to you.
They go.
No, no one is as candid as you are.
No one is as transparent as I am and a
matter of fact, some people downright don't tell us the truth.
Bust the trust so we can
never predict what's going to happen.
But if we always have
integrity, we can always solve problems.
Three sticks tied together are unbreakable.
If they're intertwined don't ever forget that when I interviewed
you you said that you never negotiated with your banks.
Can you kind of talk to you
about what was your thought process or conversation?
How did you conversate with the banks?
How did you get them on?
To your side?
I got so many nose.
I mean, I literally walked up and down Park Avenue hundreds of
financial institutions and Banks and I know no wrong business wrong time.
Not just in New York, but
Boston, Chicago, Miami, DC, Los Angeles.
I turned over every rock
and we finally got it together.
We did not give up and I learned that everyone should do well together and
it's just been my philosophy that I never want to get the edge on somebody.
I want everyone to do well.
All my partners will say that's the best return.
I've never done an investment.
They've ever had my Banks have said this guy's good for the money because he's got
capacity character and had the credit the three C's of banking and he didn't negotiate with us.
He paid his back matter of fact, he pays back early some banks that I paid
him back to early because they need the money out longer to make a better return.
So as long as everyone's always made money, that's been my philosophy and I would encourage
each and every young entrepreneur to be thankful to their investors be transparent to be accountable.
Tell them the good the bad
the ugly which I've had to do.
You will always do.
People understand rough times as long as you have integrity don't negotiate with your Banks give your investors a good
return because they'll be there the next time and the time after that when I interviewed you last time as well.
You mentioned that in a negotiation
the first person that talks loses.
Do you have a scenario where you would the other person kind of like silent for a bit
because you said that you have to put the pen across the table and not say a word.
Yeah, I once waited a week.
I wanted to make that phone call to see if they were going to
do the deal and I just like get ready to pick up the phone.
I'm going to don't do it.
I was going to pick up that phone.
Phone and do it again.
I got really anxious.
I'm like I want an answer now and
I just waited and then I got the call.
I just had a big old grin on my face.
I'm so happy.
I did not pick up that phone and call you have to
have the patience and as tough as it is suck it up.
Once you're done with the sale first person
who talks loses don't talk past the sales.
What you say never go past the close.
Have you seen some deals blow up after that?
Yeah, because people are fucking idiots.
Whoever talks first loses.
I mean when you ask
for the deal shut your mouth.
Just.
Wait it out.
After selling a company for several billion dollars.
You could have made the decision to ride off into
the sunsets to go travel the world on a yacht.
You're deciding to run for governor of
the biggest state in the United States.
Talk to me about your thought
process and why you're doing that.
I wanted to live my dream.
My dream was always to live in Beverly Hills because I grew up
in the San Fernando Valley kindergarten through high school first year of college.
And I just always had this
dream of living in Beverly Hills.
Now I could live anywhere in the world and I wanted to live my dream even
though I was going to have to come in pay tax and I interviewed all of
the candidates that were running for office just
to get the lay of my home state.
My home state.
I grew up here and I'm
like this is the best we got.
You're kidding me, right?
So I started to really
understand the state of the state.
We're not a state.
California is a country.
It's the fifth largest GDP in the world and it used to be the bully pulpit of the United States and all of a
sudden California is on defense when it should be on offense because California needs the federal government as much as the federal government needs California.
It was the greatest state in the United
States and the leadership as I interviewed them.
I had something in common.
They never talked to the best customers
of the state and they fled the state.
That's why everyone's leaving because there was no communication with the customer who can run a
state or a country without talking to its best customers and they all had nothing in common.
They never signed the front of a check.
So they didn't know what
it was like to make payroll.
They never talked to the people of the state
its customers to see what the issues are the problems.
So I started to study and
I said, you know what I've legislated.
I've created laws in different states.
I've been a regulator.
I've held court.
I've been an adjudicator and I
fixed the most broken of business.
And this is a broken.
Business.
This state is broken.
It's closed for business.
How can I open it back up for business?
So I started to talk
to the customers of the state.
I met with over 300 people and it came
down to California is not affordable livable nor workable.
How can I fix it?
I can do it with respect responsibility and results,
which I've said before and how did we get here?
Our leaders are all failed leaders because
they haven't been accountable to the customer.
They haven't executed properly and they haven't enforced the laws and
there's too many regulations regulations are good to keep bad actors out.
But if you
over regulate you can't do good business, but all these things are fixable and
our leaders in this state want to resist when we need to unify and collaborate.
That's a new level of governing
a hardcore Republicans or the hardcore Democrats.
So how about we as customers transcend all of this and have collaborative discussions with those that can actually lead now
most business people would never touch politics or policy because it's just a nasty blood-ass sport politics is a nasty game.
Why do you want to get involved?
I'm curious messy.
I've dealt with messy my entire career.
Everything about me is on the internet.
Great.
What is perceived as my opposition is my offense.
I have fixed the most broken.
I've been extorted.
I fight extortion and I'll fight
extortion for you as my customer.
There is nothing that's out there that I'm afraid of you could say anything you want
about me and I'm doing this selflessly rolling up my sleeves because I don't need the title.
I don't need the paycheck.
I'm doing this for frankly
everyone the customers of California.
It needs command and control with
somebody who's fixed the most broken.
I don't owe anyone anything.
I'm not bought and paid for by anyone.
So
I'm always going to tell you the truth.
I'm going to tell you the hard truth.
I always carry my helmet with me.
I've had missiles shot at me be my guest because I
know that I come roll up my sleeves and deliver the results.
Steven.
This was an incredible interview.
Thank you so much for having us out.
Thank you.
Good to come on my podcast.
I'll come on the podcast.
So guys make sure that you like and subscribe for amazing content coming every week with the
most successful business owners in the entire world to come in and mentor you in these videos.
And if you guys want direct mentorship with the multi-millionaires and the
billionaires and the most successful people I interview in the entire world.
All you have to do is go down to join the school of mentors the
number one community for business owners to get mentored from Legends just like Steven Klubeck.
So everybody I can't wait to
see you in our next video.
That being said, I'll see you guys soon.